Husband, look.
زوج ، انظر.
Jianxing is back.
جيانكينغ عاد.
So you do remember to come home.
لذلك تتذكر العودة إلى المنزل.
Say a little less.
قل أقل بقليل.
Jianxing, it's been so long.
Jianxing ، لقد مر وقت طويل.
Why are you only coming back now?
لماذا ستعود فقط الآن؟
Come, let your mother take a look at you.
تعال ، دع والدتك تلقي نظرة عليك.
Madam, you spoil him too much.
سيدتي ، أنت تفسده كثيرا.
Go on, tell us.
استمر ، أخبرنا.
Where did you run off to this time?
أين هربت إلى هذا الوقت؟
Just say a little less, will you?
فقط قل أقل بقليل ، أليس كذلك؟
Look how thin the child has gotten.
انظروا كيف حصل الطفل على رقيقة.
The banquet is about to start.
المأدبة على وشك البدء.
Mother even made your favorite osmanthus cake.
حتى جعلت الأم كعكة أوسمانثوس المفضلة لديك.
Come on, it's time to go home.
تعال ، حان الوقت للعودة إلى المنزل.
Brother Jianxing.
الأخ جيانكينغ.
It seems the scene brings back memories.
يبدو أن المشهد يعيد الذكريات.
Probably when you were young,
ربما عندما كنت صغيرا ،
you came here with your father, right?
أتيت إلى هنا مع والدك ، أليس كذلك؟
Lord Hu.
اللورد هو.
You have been here before too, haven't you?
لقد كنت هنا من قبل أيضًا ، أليس كذلك؟
I'm ashamed.
أشعر بالخجل.
Although I've known General Li for many years,
على الرغم من أنني عرفت الجنرال لي لسنوات عديدة ،
I've only met him a few times in the capital.
لقد قابلته عدة مرات فقط في العاصمة.
I've never set foot in Lingzhou.
لم أقم بقدمي في Lingzhou.
My lord, hurry.
ربي ، أسرع.
Hurry up, hurry up.
اسرع ، اسرع.
Move faster, a bit higher.
تحرك بشكل أسرع ، أعلى قليلا.
To the right.
إلى اليمين.
Higher.
أعلى.
Higher, higher.
أعلى ، أعلى.
To the left, to the left.
إلى اليسار ، إلى اليسار.
Is that good?
هل هذا جيد؟
A bit to the right.
قليلا إلى اليمين.
To the right.
إلى اليمين.
Excuse me, brother, may I ask—
عفوا يا أخي ، هل لي أن أسأل -
I...
أنا...
Who is that?
من ذاك؟
No idea.
لا فكرة.
Sir.
سيد.
This family is quite strange.
هذه العائلة غريبة جدا.
What are you doing? Get to work.
ماذا تفعل؟ احصل على العمل.
Don't miss the time.
لا تفوت الوقت.
Yes.
نعم.
May I ask who you are?
هل لي أن أسأل من أنت؟
I am Hu Li.
أنا هو لي.
I was formerly a broker at Guangyuan Trading Company.
كنت في السابق وسيط في شركة Guangyuan Trading Company.
Recently, I've been traveling the world with my family.
في الآونة الأخيرة ، كنت أسافر حول العالم مع عائلتي.
This is my daughter, Hu Lailei.
هذه ابنتي ، هو ليلي.
This brave young man
هذا الشاب الشجاع
is my son,
هو ابني ،
Hu Tu.
هو أنت.
This handsome young man
هذا الشاب الوسيم
is my attendant.
هو مضيفتي.
Today, I happened to pass through Lingzhou.
اليوم ، صادفت أن تمر عبر Lingzhou.
I was delighted to hear of your happy occasion.
لقد سررت لسماع مناسبة سعيدة.
So I came to offer my congratulations.
لذلك جئت لأقدم تهانينا.
I've prepared a small gift, please kindly accept it.
لقد قمت بإعداد هدية صغيرة ، يرجى قبولها.
Please, accept it quickly.
من فضلك ، قبولها بسرعة.
Thank you so much.
شكراً جزيلاً.
The wedding is scheduled for tomorrow.
من المقرر أن يكون حفل الزفاف ليوم غد.
Why don't you honored guests stay with us for a couple of days?
لماذا لا تكرم الضيوف معنا لبضعة أيام؟
Our household
منزلنا
hasn't been this lively in a long time.
لم يكن هذا حيوي منذ وقت طويل.
Thank you for your hospitality.
شكرا لك على ضيافتك.
Then we shall gladly accept your invitation.
ثم سنقبل بكل سرور دعوتك.
Very well.
جيد جدا.
Qiao'er.
تشياو.
Come with me and take our guests to their rooms.
تعال معي وخذ ضيوفنا إلى غرفهم.
Yes, Madam.
نعم يا سيدتي.
This way, please.
بهذه الطريقة ، من فضلك.
After you, sister.
بعدك يا ​​أختك.
To be honest with everyone,
أن نكون صادقين مع الجميع ،
this ritual is for my son's late wives.
هذه الطقوس هي لزوجات ابني المتأخرة.
I'm afraid they might not rest in peace.
أخشى أنهم قد لا يرتاحون في سلام.
This doesn't seem like a ceremony for the afterlife.
هذا لا يبدو وكأنه حفل للحياة الآخرة.
It feels more like a ritual to calm restless spirits.
يبدو الأمر وكأنه طقوس لتهدئة الأرواح المضطربة.
I'm sure you've all heard
أنا متأكد من أنك سمعت جميعًا
that several of my son Xu Qiyan's previous wives
أن العديد من زوجات ابني شو تشيان السابقة
all died in this very garden.
توفي كل شيء في هذه الحديقة للغاية.
There are rumors outside
هناك شائعات في الخارج
that it's the ghost of General Li Zuo causing trouble.
أن شبح الجنرال لي زو يسبب المتاعب.
That's pure nonsense.
هذا هراء نقي.
Back then, General Li once saved my husband's life.
في ذلك الوقت ، أنقذ الجنرال لي حياة زوجي.
Everyone in the Xu household
الجميع في منزل شو
is grateful for General Li's kindness.
ممتن لطف الجنرال لي.
But outsiders don't believe that.
لكن الغرباء لا يصدقون ذلك.
In recent years, whenever we've held celebrations,
في السنوات الأخيرة ، كلما عقدنا احتفالات ،
very few friends or relatives
عدد قليل جدا من الأصدقاء أو الأقارب
have been willing to come and congratulate us.
كنت على استعداد للحضور وتهنئةنا.
I don't believe there are ghosts in this world.
لا أعتقد أن هناك أشباح في هذا العالم.
But if there really are,
ولكن إذا كان هناك بالفعل ،
I'd actually like to meet one.
أود في الواقع مقابلة واحدة.
Young people should know respect and fear.
يجب أن يعرف الشباب الاحترام والخوف.
Do you know that those vengeful spirits
هل تعلم أن تلك الأرواح الانتقامية
might be watching you right now?
قد تراقبك الآن؟
I have a clear conscience.
لدي ضمير واضح.
I'm not afraid of ghosts knocking at my door.
أنا لا أخاف من الأشباح التي تطرق بابي.
Young master, this is your guest room.
سيد الشباب ، هذه هي غرفة الضيوف الخاصة بك.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Jianxing
Jianxing
Mother, I'm scared.
الأم ، أنا خائف.
Don't be afraid, Jianxing. Mother is here.
لا تخف ، jianxing. الأم هنا.
In a moment,
في لحظة ،
No matter what you see in a moment,
بغض النظر عما تراه في لحظة ،
you must be like your father,
يجب أن تكون مثل والدك ،
and be a strong and upright man, okay?
وكن رجلًا قويًا ومستقيمًا ، حسنًا؟
Okay.
تمام.
Like this,
مثله،
Mother will take you to
ستأخذك الأم إلى
the secret room where we used to play hide-and-seek.
الغرفة السرية حيث اعتدنا أن نلعب إخفاء وسعي.
We must hide well, all right?
يجب أن نختبئ جيدًا ، حسنًا؟
Okay.
تمام.
We must hide well.
يجب أن نختبئ جيدًا.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Young master.
سيد الشباب.
Qiao'er, Qiao'er.
تشياو ، تشياو.
Look what tasty treat I brought you.
انظروا إلى ما الذي أحضرته لك.
Here you go.
ها أنت ذا.
I secretly took this from the kitchen.
أخذت سرا هذا من المطبخ.
I was almost caught by my mother.
لقد اشتعلت والدتي تقريبًا.
Thank you, young master.
شكرا لك يا سيد يونغ.
Is it tasty?
هل هو حسن الطعم ؟
It's delicious.
إنه لذيذ.
I love osmanthus cake the most.
أنا أحب كعكة عثمانثوس أكثر من غيرها.
All of these are for you.
كل هذه لك.
Eat slowly, don't rush.
أكل ببطء ، لا تتسارع.
Li Jianxing
لي جيانكينغ
Run, you rascal!
ركض ، أنت راسكال!
Did you sneak into the kitchen for food again?
هل تسللت إلى المطبخ لتناول الطعام مرة أخرى؟
Stop right there!
توقف هناك!
Miss Qiao'er
ملكة جمال تشياو
Long time no see.
وقت طويل لا رؤية.
When Madam Xu just called you Qiao'er,
عندما اتصلت بك سيدتي شو فقط Qiao'er ،
I thought it was just someone with the same name.
اعتقدت أنه كان مجرد شخص يحمل نفس الاسم.
I didn't expect it to really be you.
لم أكن أتوقع أن تكون أنت حقًا.
Young master, you've changed so much over the years.
سيد الشباب ، لقد تغيرت كثيرا على مر السنين.
I almost didn't recognize you at first.
لم أتعرف عليك في البداية.
I just didn't expect all these things to happen afterward.
لم أتوقع أن تحدث كل هذه الأشياء بعد ذلك.
In a way, it was lucky.
بطريقة ما ، كان محظوظا.
You happened to sneak into the kitchen to steal some osmanthus cake.
لقد صادفت التسلل إلى المطبخ لسرقة بعض كعكة أوسمانثوس.
And fell asleep in the firewood pile.
وسقطت في كومة الحطب.
That's how you escaped the disaster.
هكذا هربت من الكارثة.
Yes.
نعم.
But ever since then,
لكن منذ ذلك الحين ،
the young master and I have been separated.
لقد تم فصل السيد الشاب وأنا.
For these twelve years,
لهذه الاثني عشر سنة ،
I haven't heard any news about you.
لم أسمع أي أخبار عنك.
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات ،
life must have been hard for you.
يجب أن تكون الحياة صعبة بالنسبة لك.
I'm alright.
أنا بخير.
But what about you?
لكن ماذا عنك؟
Why are you working as a maid again?
لماذا تعمل كخادمة مرة أخرى؟
I'm just a poor family's daughter.
أنا مجرد ابنة عائلة فقيرة.
Being a maid is my fate.
كوني خادمة هو مصيري.
Besides,
بجانب،
Madam Li treated me very well back then.
سيدتي لي عاملتني جيدًا في ذلك الوقت.
I still have feelings for this place.
لا يزال لدي مشاعر لهذا المكان.
There's always a bit of attachment in my heart.
هناك دائمًا القليل من التعلق في قلبي.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
Miss Qiao'er,
ملكة جمال تشياو ،
can you do me a favor?
هل يمكنك أن تفعل لي معروفا؟
Please don't tell anyone about my identity.
من فضلك لا تخبر أحدا عن هويتي.
Including
مشتمل
the people who are traveling with me.
الأشخاص الذين يسافرون معي.
Don't worry, young master.
لا تقلق يا سيد الشباب.
I understand.
أفهم.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Then I won't disturb your rest any longer.
ثم لن أزعج راحتك بعد الآن.
Brother Jianxing, sword—
الأخ جيانكينغ ، السيف -
Brother Jianxing, you really are quite the ladies' man.
الأخ جيانكينغ ، أنت حقا رجل السيدات.
Judging by Lord Hu's tone,
إذا حكمنا من خلال لهجة اللورد هو ،
he sounds jealous.
يبدو غيورًا.
There was a case at the Dali Court recently.
كانت هناك قضية في محكمة دالي مؤخرًا.
A playboy,
playboy ،
because he flirted everywhere,
لأنه غازل في كل مكان ،
was torn apart by several women.
تمزق من قبل العديد من النساء.
Brother Jianxing,
الأخ جيانكينغ ،
you'd better be careful.
من الأفضل أن تكون حذراً.
Thank you for your concern, Lord Hu.
شكرا لك على اهتمامك ، اللورد هو.
I, Li Jianxing, have a clear conscience.
أنا ، لي جيانكينغ ، لدي ضمير واضح.
I'm not afraid of ghosts knocking at my door at midnight.
أنا لا أخاف من الأشباح التي تطرق بابي في منتصف الليل.
What brings you to me?
ما الذي يقلبك لي؟
Madam Xu is inviting us to a banquet tonight.
سيدتي شو تدعونا إلى مأدبة الليلة.